

QA/DEV ENGINEER

Details

Ireland, Cork +3530852023712 dmtrmsc@gmail.com

NATIONALITY

Ukrainian

DATE OF BIRTH **29/03/1993**

Links

LinkedIn

Facebook

Telegram

Github

Download this CV

Skills

Git

SQL

PHP

Selenium

Cypress

CI/CD

Grafana

TeamCity

Docker

Agile Testing

Peformance Testing

Sentry

Kibana

Linux/Unix

Summary

I'm an Engineer with 6 years of experience in quality assurance, 4 of which are related to automation. I have experience in Selenium, PHP, Docker, Cypress & CI/CD. I understand the difference between testing and the task of quality assurance, and I will do my best to ensure that the quality of the product does not fall, but grows in the long term.

Employment

Engineer, Avito Tech

NOVEMBER 2020 - APRIL 2022

Globally, our team was engaged in the implementation of the technical task - the removal of logic from the monolith into separate microservices on go.

Tasks included:

- organized the testing process in the team (workflow: implemented the process of initiating and processing defects, adjusted the life cycle of working on tasks by adding new statuses and introducing criteria by which the task can be checked independently or transferred to a test so that another engineer can test it)
- moved more than 200 tests and 40 helper methods from the monolith to 4 different microservices with refactoring and pull request launch settings. Helper methods have been rewritten to use the gRPC protocol, and authorization has been accelerated by authorization methods through fast cookies.
- completed more than 15 tasks of simple backend tasks from the general backlog (creating endpoints, transferring logic to a new service on Go, deleting old code, transferring handles to gRPC)
- set up non-functional metrics and alerts for worldservice in production

Middle Automation QA Engineer, Avito

JULY 2018 - NOVEMBER 2020

Team: Support Systems (Trust&Safety cluster)

Product:

- Helpcenter an external platform for creating an appeal, available from 4 platforms (Web, Mobile, iOS, Android)
- Helpdesk (internal system for working with requests) + WFM (system for calculating metrics when working on requests)

Tasks included:

- work with documentation: updated unit test model (more than 600 test cases)
- implementation of agile testing
- participation in the development process: participation in grooming, planning, discovery, and offering their own options for solving problems. And also at the time of these meetings, a draft was already being formed with a set of scenarios for testing. This draft was written into the task, and even before the task was completed, the developers could see critical scenarios that should be taken into account when implementing this task.
- control over the development process: monitored the life cycle of the defect and suggested to the team things that should be improved.
- research work: I reproduced bugs based on information from Sentry, conducted exploratory testing of previously unknown functionality, sorted out

API Testing

A/B Testing

Automated Testing

Manual Testing

Functional Testing

Languages

Russian

English

Ukranian

difficult-to-reproduce bugs based on auxiliary data received from users of our system and reproduced them.

- acting as a release manager: performed the functions of a release manager, rolling out features for a percentage using canary releases
- carrying out load testing: I prepared the environment and ran closed/open tests to determine the Capacity in a special performance environment and then repeated the tests in production. Based on the results, I wrote a report with data attached (logs, information from Grafana) and made assumptions because of what a bottleneck could form and what could be improved.

Optional:

I served as a team leader for a team of 6 from October 2019 to July 2020.

Middle QA Engineer, Rucenter

MAY 2017 - JUNE 2018

Creation of test scenarios, preparation of a test plan, preparation of test benches, verification of defect fixes, maintenance of test documentation, analysis of errors in log files

Software tester, Bifit

APRIL 2016 - MAY 2017

Functional testing of web applications through the user interface.

Education

Engineer, Moscow Aviation Institute, Moscow

SEPTEMBER 2010 - MARCH 2016

Information systems and technologies

Courses

PHP for Beginners, Udemy

SEPTEMBER 2019 - DECEMBER 2019

Java Foundation Cource, ecollege.ie

JUNE 2022

Books

Agile testing

PHP 7

Clean Code: A Handbook of Agile Software

Docker